Ramesh Rajput

Full Stack Java Developer

Navi Mumbai, Maharashtra

Summary of Qualifications

A Software Developer with 1.5 year of experience and strong grasping power.

Have experience in designing and implementing solutions and is looking for a

challenging role in a progressive organization to utilize my technical, database,

and management skills for the growth of the organization.

Work Experience

Jr. Java Developer

Capgemini India Private Limited

Duration: October 2018 to Present

(November 2018 to Present)

Tools: Java, J2EE, Spring, Oracle SQL, jUnit, Tomcat, JAX-WS

Role and Responsibilities:

• Maintaining 8 different applications in this particular project.

• Developing new feature changes according to client requirement and

giving them the best solutions.

• Interacting with other application team members on regular basis to keep

application intact.

• Validating application deployment in various environment servers.

• Expertly manage technical support operations, carefully troubleshooting issues to identify root causes and prevent recurrence.

Education

BE in Computer Science

Mumbai University

Graduation: 2017

HSC

Mumbai University

Graduation: 2013

SSC

Mumbai University

Graduation: 2011

Key Skills

- Java (1 year)
- Tomcat (1 year)
- Sql (1 year)
- J2Ee (1 year)
- Spring (1 year)
- Hibernate (1 year)
- Jquery
- Html
- Css

• Angular 5

Certificates

Oracle Certified Associate August 2018 to Present

Oracle Certified Java SE 8 Programmer